(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-10T00:16:20.066223",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Reine B'Day Classroom: Field Trip - Food & Games with Akai Haato
Attention please, mother feathers!
Today, I've got some amazing guests here to celebrate my birthday with me.
Everyone, come on out!
Happy Birthday!
Happy Birthday, Reine!
Wow! It's like...
It's like we're in Indone...
We are in Indonesia!
I'm ready for a vacation, ladies.
Let's start our Indonesia vacation!
Anyways, we have Calliope!
Oh, hi guys! Hi, minna-san!
Oh, hi guys! Hi, everyone!
It's me, Mori Calliope from Hololive English Myth!
What's going on? Hanmetsu wa koko desu desu. Let's have fun together!
What's going on? Ruin is here! Let's have fun together!
Yatta!
Yay!
We have Takanashi Kiara!
Yes! Ki-ki-ri-ki! I am also from Hololive English Myth.
I am Takanashi Kiara, and finally...
...finally, I made it to Indonesia! My second time!
And we have... Zeta!
And finally, I'm back in Indonesia!
What a cute cat! Oh, what a cute cat!
Did you bring some Churu? Churu? You want Churu?
No, no!
She hates that.
Is this your new cat?
Yes, my new house cat, you like her?
Oh, she's so cute!
For this year's birthday...
...I've put together lots of fun activities!
So I went on location shoots in both Indonesia and Japan...
...and...
...we'll also be playing games that are popular in Indonesia with these wonderful guests!
And guess what?
I'll be performing a brand new song at the end of the stream!
So don't miss it and stay until the very end!
Yes! Don't leave! Don't leave!
Listen to her, or else...
The peafowl is talking, listen to her.
So first, let's take a look at the video from my location shoot in Indonesia!
Let's go!
Attention please!
I'm Pavolia Reine reporting from BSD City, Indonesia.
I've talked a lot about spicy food in Indonesia, but...
...today, I will be introducing a wider variety of Indonesian food...
...for everyone to get to know it even better!
Can anybody guess what we'll be eating today?
Here we are at Jalarasa The Breeze, BSD!
Embark on a culinary journey through the enchanting flavors of Indonesia at Jalarasa Indonesian Cuisine.
We are proud to bring you the authentic tastes of this archipelago nation.
Join us celebrate Indonesia's culinary tapestry!
First, we have perkedel jagung.
Perkedel jagung are sweet corn fritters served with sambal roa.
Mmm, you know how much I talk about this sambal.
Indonesia has a wide variety of sambal from different regions.
Sambal roa is a Manado specialty, and it is mainly made from chili...
...and smoked ballyhoo fish.
Mari kita coba.
Let's try it.
Enak... Yummy!
Delicious... Yummy!
Next, we're gonna take some Tahu Lada Garam.
Mmm, salt and pepper tofu, yummy!
Ooh, it's salt-and-pepper fried tofu complete with Indonesian aromatics.
Let's have a taste!
Hmm, this is like buttery flavor. I like it so much.
Hmm, this has like a buttery flavor. I like it so much.
And this one is a Sundanese specialty called karedok.
It's a traditional salad that uses a rich peanut sauce.
Mmm, it has green eggplants, cucumbers, lemon basil, long beans, as well as bean sprouts.
So fresh!
Segar banget!
So refreshing!
Next up, we're going to go eat some fish!
This is also my first time eating this fish or even looking at this fish.
Did you guys know that a fish called kudu-kudu existed?
This is Kudu-Kudu Telur Asin...
Mmm, ini...
Mmm, this is...
So Indonesia really has such a rich cultured cuisine.
I've never eaten this before.
This is one of Jala Rasa's specialties.
Haha, even the skin is so tough!
So this is a boxfish, apparently.
This boxfish is served with a very popular telor asin sauce.
This boxfish is served with a very popular salted egg sauce.
The texture is membal-membal, you know?
The texture is springy, you know?
Enak banget.
It's so delicious.
I would recommend you guys eat this.
Yeah, yeah, I get what they're saying. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, it tastes a little bit like chicken, it's so unique.
You guys definitely need to try it, even like Indo bros, you guys got to try this.
Okay, so this is Iga Sapi Bakar Cabe Ijo.
Okay, so this is grilled beef ribs with green chili.
It's a Javanese specialty...
...smoked ribs served with sambal ijo, a.k.a. green chili.
...grilled ribs served with green chili sambal.
So unlike the previous sambal we had, this one is made of only green chilis and other aromatics.
So, the iga itself is sweet,
So, the ribs themselves are sweet,
so combined with this spicy and a little bit savory sambal ijo condiment,
so combined with this spicy and a little bit savory green chili condiment,
it makes for a really good dish.
Ini dagingnya empuk juga.
This meat is also tender.
The meat is so soft, I recommend this one.
And this one's a classic.
You know what it is.
It's the beloved Nasi Goreng!
It's the beloved fried rice!
So we have this traditional chicken Nasi Goreng that's cooked with terasi, yeah guys.
So we have this traditional chicken fried rice that's cooked with shrimp paste, yeah guys.
Terasi is a local shrimp or krill paste.
Smells so good.
I think it's known as belacan in Malaysia and also kapi in Thailand, yeah.
Let's try this.
It's a mix of...
...sweet and spicy and savory.
...sweet, spicy, and savory.
And as usual when you're eating Nasi Goreng, don't forget the kerupuk!
And as usual when you're eating fried rice, don't forget the crackers!
This is Nasi Liwet.
Nasi Liwet is a Sundanese specialty rice that is topped with...
...salted fish, fried shallots, and more salted fish.
You can taste the depth of flavors.
Enak banget, sumpah ini enggak bohong.
It's so delicious, I swear I'm not lying.
No lie lie, this is so good.
And this is a Jakarta specialty, Kangkung Hotplate!
Siapa yang suka makan kangkung di sini?
Who likes to eat water spinach here?
So this morning glory is cooked with oyster sauce
and topped with quail eggs and shrimp.
Look at the shrimp, there is also shrimp and seafood.
And this is Coto Makassar,
a Makassar specialty beef soup flavored with cloves and braised peanuts.
The history of Coto Makassar dates back to the 16th century...
...during the era of the Gowa Kingdom.
Coto was a special dish that symbolized wealth and luxury,
as it was said to be served only to kings and nobles.
Like me!
Let's give it a taste.
Yummy.
Clove itu itu loh guys, cengkeh, cengkeh.
Cloves are those, guys, cloves, cloves.
So fresh, megar-megar!
So fresh, so satisfying!
Now that we've finished eating all the savory food,
which was really, really good,
now it's time to close it with a dessert!
This time we have Es Pisang Ijo!
Es Pisang Ijo literally means...
...iced green bananas. As you can see...
...look at these beautiful green bananas!
The bananas are wrapped in a green flour dough...
...and is served with coconut milk and pandan. Let's give it a try!
Look at this, it also has sweet coconut rice pudding...
...Indonesian tapioca pearls with a beautiful pink color...
...condensed milk...
...and a special Ambon banana syrup.
I really, really like the coconut rice pudding.
Taste so good.
There's a little bit of savory complimenting the sweetness.
Wow, that was a crazy meal!
I can't believe the different flavor profile of every dish!
Mmm, from the Jagung Perkedel...
Mmm, from the corn fritters...
...up until the dessert, mmm!
And the portions are pretty big, so if you guys come here,
I recommend you to come with your friends and share.
That's why everybody...
...come visit Indonesia!
Everybody come to Indonesia!
But in case some of you are curious...
...but aren't ready to come to Indonesia...
well, stay tuned for the next part coming up!
Hey! It's Reine, back in the studio!
Did everyone enjoy our shoot in Indonesia?
The food was so delicious.
I really wish one day you guys could go to Indonesia. Please have a try!
All right, next up, we're going to play our first game! Yay!
We have... We have two guests for today!
So let's move our bodies and have a blast together!
All right, let's get started. Our first game is this!
Sorry, sorry, there's a bit of distraction going on over here.
Oh my god, there's a feral animal over here.
A feral animal! Did you guys even notice this right here? What is this?
Everybody gather around, gather around.
What is that? Apa sih?
What is that? What is it?
Reine, you've got to tell us what it is. I've never seen anything like that in my life.
Looks delicious, though, right? Totally don't know what that is.
Is it like... sembei?
Kind of, yeah. Like a rice cake or something?
Tofu tofu! Tofu? Tofu.
Okay, okay, we'll explain.
So, this one will be an individual competition. It is not a team battle.
And everyone will be competing against each other. Got it?
Ooh, competition! Okay, okay.
So, this one will be called the Royal Kerupuk Contest!
Yeah, this is kerupuk.
Yeah, crunchy crunchy. What exactly is it? Is it like a food?
Yeah, it is. It's so pretty, though, for being a food.
Yeah, so if you see the start line is over there...
...and then the line on this side is the turn around line. So you go like choo-choo-choo-choo!
And then when the signal is given, you go to the starting line and you have to do...
...five squats!
Five squats? I did five squats yesterday!
No, no, no, listen. The good thing is that there is no punishment game...
...because this is the punishment!
And then after you do five squats, you go run towards here...
...and without using your hands, you jump and grab it with your mouth.
And then... After five squats? Yeah, my legs will be tired.
You can finish it with your hands, yeah. And then when you're done, just be like, 'Hey, I'm done!' And then you run here.
And then... you just shake your butt ten times. I'll be watching!
Yeah, ten. Or you want twenty? No, no, no, ten is good! Ten is perfect!
Twenty just for more clarify? No, no, ten is perfect. Alright, good to know.
Alright, so like you do ten, and then once we count and give the okay, you run back.
And then straight to the back, you know, the finish line, and then, yeah, the fastest one wins.
Oh, okay! Okay!
Is this an Indonesian game? Yeah, pretty much.
It's a kerupuk eating contest. But I don't think you shake your butt. You don't shake your butt?
We gotta spice it up! It's a Reine original move, okay. It's an upgraded version! Yeah!
Sure, sounds good to me.
Okay, well there's a bit of a height difference but... it should be fine.
Oh yeah, I mean we're all pretty tall except... Except me!
This is kind of unfair. We can measure our height. We can measure our height.
She just has to jump higher. Cats can jump pretty high normally.
I'm not a cat! You are! You're a cat.
Okay fine, how about... Secret agents are really good at jumping. Okay okay, I'll jump really high.
Well, looking at our heights, I guess me and Calli can go first.
Okay, okay, yay!
So, Kiara and Zeta, you will be judging our hip shaking, so you can stand...
I feel like Kiara is going to definitely give you more points, though, because she definitely wants to see that.
She wants to see you like throwing it back.
Well, I want to see you! I can be pretty strict when it comes to butt shaking.
Maybe because she wants to see more, she'll make you do twice as many.
Nah, nah, nah, we'll see, we'll see. Got to be fair.
Twenty for more clarify? Oh, no thank you. Ten is a perfect number.
Twenty for more clarify. Yeah, sure, more clarify.
Oh, come on!
Kiara and Zeta, please give us the start signal, okay?
Okay!
Should we say it in Indonesian? Okay. Tiga, dua, satu...
Should we say it in Indonesian? Okay. Three, two, one...
Okay, I'm ready.
Tiga, dua, satu, go!
Three, two, one, go!
One, two, three, four, five!
Go, go, go!
Jump, jump!
Oh, she got it!
Oh, so fast! So fast!
It's so crunchy.
Oh my god, it's going up!
No!
Very crunchy.
Speed eating contest!
They can't even talk.
Mogu mogu mogu mogu!
Munch, munch, munch, munch!
Mogu mogu!
Munch, munch!
Don't choke! Don't choke!
Breathe, breathe!
Don't choke!
Exhale, inhale.
Mogu mogu mogu.
Munch, munch, munch.
They are inhaling the food.
They both look pretty much done.
The last chewing!
Go! Shake that booty!
One, two, three, four, five!
Did you do the last squat?
Go, go, go!
Did they finish at the same time?
Photo finish.
Seems like a tie.
Hey, quit shaking that ass!
I actually think that I gave you 15, by the way.
Keep shaking that ass!
Yabe...
Oh boy...
That seemed like a tie. Good job, though.
It was pretty much a photo finish...
...but maybe we can check who made it to the finish line first?
Just like my umas.
Do you two have an idea who made it first?
I don't know. I feel like it was pretty much the exact same.
We can't be sure.
You were pretty synced up with the mogu mogu also.
You were pretty synced up with the munching also.
That surprised me. I didn't know that it was that hard to eat.
It was really dry.
Yeah, it was really dry. I didn't know that.
Reine, have you ever eaten a kerupuk so fast?
No, not usually.
We eat it with drinks and other food.
There was no water.
I got crumbs all over your beautiful tile. I'm sorry.
Oh, yeah.
It's okay. No need to clean because next we're going, right?
But for now, I guess we shall give the points to...
Ah, we got it!
We got it! What?
The results are in!
Please announce the times for us.
Okay, we got the results.
So...
Mori Calliope finished with a time of 55.1 seconds!
Eh? What?
Not yet, not yet. And Reine, it was a close one...
Finished with a time of 55.5 seconds!
That's 0.4 seconds difference!
0.4!
That was really close.
That was a great fight.
Good game, good game.
Yeah, rough.
Now we can take it easy.
Yeah, let's get a drink.
Is it our turn?
Oh, yes. While we take a break.
Now you guys get to eat the super dry snack.
Yay!
Zeta, get ready! And shake your ass!
That's the part Kiara is most excited about, of course.
If I ever get to it.
Okay.
Let's get into position.
Okay, sounds good.
See you later.
Here we go!
Bird versus Cat.
Wait, which one's the bird and which one's the cat?
I'm the bird.
Oh, okay.
She really just doesn't want to be a cat.
Yeah, anything but.
But it's okay. Less discussion, more ass shaking.
How do we count in Indonesian?
Tiga... tiga.
Three... three.
Dua... dua.
Two... two.
Satu... satu. Go... go.
One... one. Go... go.
Go! Oh, wait!
No, no, no, not yet. Get back there, no cheating!
Remember to squat five times.
And they need to be good squats.
Okay, good squats.
Tiga, dua, satu. Okay, got you.
Three, two, one. Okay, got you.
Tiga, dua, satu, go!
Three, two, one, go!
One, two...
Three, four...
Five! You guys are slow, come on!
Oh, dang.
She really just went for it.
Oh my lord, they are having a hard time.
You got it, Kiara!
You got to try again, you got to try again.
You're eating nothing!
Ganbare!
Keep going!
Jump! Jump! Jump! You can just jump, just jump!
Jump, jump, jump, jump!
Ah!
Oh, try, try again, try again.
Try again. No, higher! No, lower, lower.
Maybe like...
You got it, you got it, you got it!
Eat, eat, eat! Come on!
Get down, get down! Come on, you got this!
Yum, yum! Ooh, yummy. Pretend it's a delicious macaroon.
Oh my god, are you okay?
Ooh, yummy. Delicious macaroon.
Yogurt?
Use the saliva, use the saliva.
Just like, generate some saliva. You got this. Just, just keep... you got this.
Macaroons! Yum, yummy. So sugary, sweet...
Sweet, delicious macaroons.
It's like, what's your favorite flavor?
Done!
Macaroons, and like...
She likes sweet...
I ate it as soon as I could!
Go, go, go! Kiara, you got this! Kiara, you got this! Come on!
0, 0... yeah, 0.45?
Good job, good job!
You got it, so finish it. Ten times, ten times.
0 to 0.45...
Oh my god, I did it! I did it!
Shake that butt! You got to shake it. One, two, three, four, five...
...six, seven, eight, nine, ten!
Oh, Kiara's shaking that ass!
Wow, we're just slowpokes over here.
I've heard that line somewhere before.
I've heard that line too.
This song got you hypnotized.
My favorite clock says that.
Stop! Stop! Good job.
Your eating may have been better, but my ass-shaking may have been better.
It was pretty good, it was pretty good.
I'll upload it as a separate video. Yeah, that thing was going crazy.
She was doing circles with it, it was crazy.
I wonder who won. Yeah, okay, let's... and now, both of our times multiplied by two.
Okay, let's go, center, center.
Hi, hi! Let's go, let's go!
Let's hear the time. Where's the time? We need a time.
Mmh, they are cooking, they are cooking our time.
They'd be cooking, okay. They'll figure it out.
Stream's figuring it out, my full-length MV, "Reine."
Yes, definitely don't miss it.
Yay! Damn, I jumped as high as I could, but...
You were really going crazy. You were doing it with respect, like a superhero.
You're flying. Like a superhero.
Thank you, thank you, I tried hard.
But Zeta, the short cat, she just...
Cats, they jump really high. The results are in!
Oh, we got the time! Oh, wait.
Oh boy, okay.
And it's please...
Wait, really?
Eh, okay...
Are we sure this is correct? That's crazy.
Okay, wow. So, Kiara finished with a time of 1 minute and 42 seconds!
Yay! Pretty good!
It is good!
And it looks like Zeta finished with a time of 1 minute 40 seconds.
Yeah! 1 minute 40 seconds!
Congratulations!
That's crazy. So, so, in total...
In total, well, in total, so after the first game...
...with 55.1, what was it? I think, why?
55.1?
Calli, Calli has the fastest time!
Calli wins! Calli wins!
I did it!
Kiara was so extra, though, with her...
Thank you, thank you, thank you. I get extra points.
That was so good, that was awesome. You really were doing circles with it. It was crazy.
Camera, camera, camera! She's shaking that ass!
You can't get that for free.
You missed it! You're not going to get it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! Maybe you can get it for free.
Sorry, Reine, sorry, sorry.
No, it's fine, it's fine.
We will clip that and upload a separate video of that.
Anyways, I'm so glad it worked out because I really wanted you guys to try the kerupuk. I'm sorry it was dry and stuff.
There's drinks over there, probably.
It was fun, right?
It feels like I grew up in Indonesia now.
Right! Indonesian now. Yeah, it feels like I grew up in Indonesia too.
It feels like I grew up in Indonesia too.
Thanks for sharing that part of your childhood with us. It was fun.
Okay, I guess it's time to move on to the next game, maybe?
I'm okay, are there more games?
Yeah, but before that, before we continue...
I would like everyone to watch a little bit of the footage from my Japan location shoot!
Oh, there's going to be more food!
So, here we go!
Yay!
Hey, so did anyone get jealous watching me enjoy my delicious meal in Indonesia earlier?
Well, don't worry, cuz you can eat ID food right here in Tokyo too!
I'm at an Indonesian restaurant in Roppongi, Tokyo today.
The restaurant is called Wayang Bali,
and it's a lovely place where you can enjoy a wide variety of delicious Indonesian cuisine!
But, I want to share my food with someone!
So, let's introduce these dishes to a very special JP member!
Yay! Haachama-chama! Worldwide traveling idol, Akai Haato!
Yay!
Thank you so much, Haachama, for coming!
Thank you, too!
Let's head inside and see what delicious dishes they have today!
Yeah, let's go! I'm so excited!
お腹すいた〜 / 私も〜
I'm hungry~ / Me too~
料理が楽しみ！ / イェーイ！
I'm excited! / Yay!
So, I have invited you out to eat with me to celebrate my birthday this year!
Happy Birthday! / Thank you so much for coming!
So like, for this year, I wanted to try something new...
...and celebrate my Indonesian culture by sharing it with everyone!
We ate instant noodles together before, right? / Yeah!
So, that's why I wanted you to try some real Indonesian food this time.
Yes! So you can level up!
You can level up your... / Level up!
...Indonesian level! / Next time I go to Indonesia! / Yes!
There are also like spicy food here, but...
...I think they won't be as spicy as the spicy noodles, so you don't have to worry.
But you're excited about spicy, right? / Yeah!
I want spicy!
Spicy! / Pedan! Pedan!
Pedas! / Pedas! Pedas! / Yes!
Haachama, pedas lover. / Pedas love! I love pedas! / Me too, I love pedas!
How do you say "I love pedas" in Indonesian?
Aku suka...
...pedas. / Aku suka pedas!
Yeah! That means "I love spicy". / Aku suka pedas! / Yay!
See? I'm slowly turning Haachama Indonesian...
...by feeding her Indonesian food! / Yeah, yeah! / Yay!
Oh~ so this is the menu! / Yeah!
Oh, it's also written here: "Indonesian food vocabulary."
So if you want to learn Indonesian, there are so many words here!
「辛い」＝ PEDAS.
"Karai" = pedas.
Pedas, yeah! I love pedas! / Yes.
This is... there are "kukus", "bakar".
Bakar? / Bakar, bakar!
"R" is rolling. "Bakar" is "to grill". / "To grill"? / Yes!
"To stir-fry" is "tumis". / Tumis! / Yeah.
Indonesian already! Indonesian school starts now!
Satay! / Do you know satay?
焼き... 串... 串焼き！
Grilled... skewers... grilled skewers!
Yes! It's Indonesian grilled skewers! / Oh!
Do you know what tempe is? Trumpet?
Tempe? Tempe? Tempe? Oh... I don't know. / Mmh.
So, tempe is like, what is it? In Indonesia...
...it's kind of like the primary source of protein. / Protein? / Yes!
Wow!
And then, I think they kind of use the same base materials as natto.
Natto? Really? / Yeah, so they're like cousins!
Protein natto! / Yes! Do you like natto?
Ah, I like natto. / Oh, really?
I haven't... can you eat it?
I've tried, but I don't know if I like it. / Ah...
How do you like natto?
まぜまぜ。まぜまぜ。 / まぜまぜ、オッケーオッケー。ミックス。
Mix it. Mix it. / Mix it, okay okay. Mix.
So, if you like natto, then maybe you will like tempe! / Oh, yay! Tempe!
There's also, this is also spicy: dabu-dabu. / Dabu-dabu! I like the name!
Fried chicken with... yeah, dabu-dabu is the sauce name.
And there's also spicy chicken: ayam pedas. / Ooh!
Well, anyway, we went through a lot of the menu!
So, I guess we should order a bunch and we can try them all!
But we should also give you, since you're turning Indonesian...
...we need to give you an Indonesian introduction! / Oh, yeah! Let's do that!
So, can you say your introduction just in your normal way?
Haachama-chama! Worldwide traveling idol, Akai Haato!
Okay, okay. So, in Indonesian, that would be...
Haachama-chama!
Idola... / Idola!
...yang... / Idola yang...
...menjelajahi... / Menjelajahi...
...dunia... / Dunia! / Akai Haato.
Menjelajahi dunia, Akai Haato! / Yeah!
What is the first one? / Idola...
Idola! / ...yang...
Idola yang! / ...menjelajahi...
...menjelajahi... / ...dunia.
...dunia! / Idola yang menjelajahi dunia...
...Akai Haato!
dunia, Akai Haato!
...world, Akai Haato!
Wow! Woohoo! Yay!
Oh, it looks like our food is on the way.
I'm starting to get hungry...
Let's eat!
Okay, our first dish has arrived.
This is tempe! Tempe!
Are you hungry? I'm hungry! Let's eat!
And this is the sauce...
...that they give, yeah, so we can eat together.
...that they give, so we can eat together.
Sweet one?
Is it sweet?
I think. Is it sweet or spicy?
I think so. Is it sweet or spicy?
I have like chopsticks and spoons...
I have chopsticks and spoons,
...but staff said I can eat with my hands so I'll eat with my hands.
...but the staff said I can eat with my hands, so I will.
Oishi ne! Mmm.
It's delicious! Mmm.
First I'll try it without the sauce.
I'll try! Dip the sauce.
I'll try! Let's dip it in the sauce.
The sauce is like... yeah, it's kind of sweet, yeah.
The sauce has a sweet flavor to it.
Can I try this?
Can I try this too?
The spicy one! There's a new...
It's the spicy one! We have another...
...spicy one. This is more spicy probably.
...spicy sauce here. This one is probably quite spicy.
Yay! Let's try it!
Ah, gimana deh! (laughter)
Ah, what are you doing! (laughter)
We can rescue it with chopsticks.
It's spicy! Mmm, I like it.
More spicy than the normal sauce. Are you okay?
It's spicier than the regular sauce! Are you okay?
You can feel the spiciness, right?
You can feel the spiciness, right? (giggles)
Which one do you like better? This or this? This one!
Which sauce did you like better? This or this? This one!
Yay! Haachama loves spicy, okay!
The next one we have Tahu Isi!
Tahu Isi is fried tofu! Fried tofu!
Look at this, so crispy!
Look at this, it's so crispy!
(crunch) Oh, it sounds good.
What is this tofu like? But if we split this...
This is tofu, but if we split this open...
Bisa kagak ya dibagi... Mmm...
Let's see if we can split it... Mmm...
There! This is the isi! Oh!
Look! There's the filling inside! Oh!
It has bean sprouts, carrot...
It has bean sprouts, carrots...
...a lot of things, so you should give it a try.
...and all kinds of things, so you should try some!
Do you want to try some? Yeah! Let's eat!
Do you want to share some? Yeah! Let's eat!
And I think it's very good if you dip it in this sauce, yeah.
I think it goes really well with this spicy sauce.
Ooh! Spicy, spicy, spicy!
Look at Haachama, already eating with her hands, very Indonesian!
Look, Haachama is already eating with her hands, true Indonesian style!
Mmm! Mmm!
Oh, it's chewy! A little bit.
Oh, it's kind of chewy! A little bit.
This sauce is so spicy! I didn't expect it to be so spicy.
This sauce is so spicy! I didn't expect it to be this spicy.
The more you eat, the spicier it gets!
Yeah, exactly! The more you chew, the spicier it gets.
So yeah, you can easily see this in Indonesia...
You can easily find this in Indonesia...
...in maybe, like street stalls.
...at things like street food stalls.
They're sold at street stalls or by the road, so it's like street food.
They're sold at street stalls or by the roadside, so it's a popular street food.
Ah, I want to go to a street stall! Yes, yes!
Ah, I really want to go to a street food stall! Yes, definitely!
Okay, yay, next one! Oh, there's lemon...
This is called Ayam Sisit! Ayam Sisit! Yeah.
So this is boiled or fried chicken with rich aromatic spices...
So this is boiled or fried chicken seasoned with rich aromatic spices...
...and they are just shredded...
...and they shred it so the flavors soak in well...
Like you see, it's shredded, and it uses a spice blend called Bumbu Genep.
As you can see, it's shredded, and it uses a spice blend called Bumbu Genep.
That's the seasoning name. I don't think this is as spicy as earlier.
That's the name of the seasoning. I don't think this one is as spicy as the previous dish.
We can try this. Usually we eat this with rice, but they didn't give us any...
Let's try it. Usually we eat this with rice, but they didn't give us any...
...because there's still more food coming!
...probably because there's still plenty of food to come!
So let's try this. Let's try it.
Not spicy, right? Mmm.
It's not spicy, right? Mmm.
I don't know exactly what's in here, but it has aromatic spices.
I don't know exactly what spices are in here, but you can taste the aromatics.
Ah, it's like... it's like ika... dried ika!
Ah, it's like... it's like squid... dried squid!
Like shredded squid, but this is shredded chicken.
Like shredded squid, except this is shredded chicken!
It might be really good with alcohol. Like beer, beer!
It would probably go really well with alcohol. Like with beer!
Yes! Like otsumami. Yeah, otsumami! Mmm.
Yes! Like a bar snack. Yeah, a bar snack! Mmm.
Ooh! And now the main dishes are out!
This is Ayam Sambal Matah! Ayam Sambal Matah!
Yeah, Ayam is chicken, and Sambal Matah is the type of sambal.
Ayam means chicken, and Sambal Matah is the type of sambal.
Sambal? Samba?! Dancing?! No, no!
Sambal? Samba?! Like the dance?! No, no!
SambaじゃなくてSambalね
It's Sambal, not Samba.
辛い調味料だよ
It's a spicy condiment.
生の素材を細かく刻んでいて
Raw ingredients are finely chopped...
酸味と辛味を生かしつつ
...highlighting the sourness and spiciness...
熱いオイルをかけて仕上げるの
...and it's finished by pouring hot oil over it.
これはお肉だよね？
This is meat, right?
鶏肉だよ
It's chicken.
食べたことがある味がする！
I've tasted this flavor before!
インドネシアの麺料理かな
Maybe like Indonesian noodles?
言われてみれば似ているものがあるね
Now that you mention it, they do taste similar.
私の好物の軟骨だよ
This is cartilage, my favorite!
もっと食レポに集中しなきゃなんだろうけど
I know we should be focusing on the review...
美味しすぎて食べることしかできない
...but it's so delicious, I can't stop eating!
しょうがないよね
It can't be helped, right?
私も軟骨を食べてみよっと
I'm going to try the cartilage too.
軟骨はどこかな？
Where is the cartilage?
Sambalに使われているオニオン食べてみる？
Do you want to try the onions in the sambal?
生だけじゃなくオニオンフライもあるよ
There are fried onions, not just raw ones.
ミーゴレンみたいな味がする
It tastes like Mie Goreng.
確かに酸味を感じられるね
I can definitely taste the sourness.
辛さはあんまりないね
It's not very spicy.
辛味というより塩味があるよね
It's more salty than spicy, right?
インドネシアには色んな種類のSambalがあって
There are many types of sambal in Indonesia.
これとはまた違う種類もあるから
And some are completely different from this one.
機会があれば他の種類も試してほしいな
I hope you get a chance to try other types as well.
そろそろ辛いのが食べたいでしょ
You've been wanting to eat something spicy, right?
早く食べたいから食べていい？
I want to eat it soon, can I have a bite?
これがピーナッツソースなんだけど
This is the peanut sauce.
すっごく美味しいんだよ
It's super delicious!
鶏肉をピーナッツソースで食べたことないや
I've never had chicken with peanut sauce before.
今日は鶏肉をたくさん食べてるね！
We're eating a lot of chicken today!
インドネシア料理は鶏肉をよく使うよね
Indonesian cuisine uses chicken a lot.
すごくクリーミーだね
It's so creamy.
ピーナッツソース以外でも甘い醤油を使うこともあるんだよ
Besides peanut sauce, sweet soy sauce is also used sometimes.
同じ鶏肉でも味付けが全然違うよね
Even with the same chicken, the flavor is completely different.
調味料でかなり変わるよね
The seasoning makes a huge difference.
次はどれを食べたい？
Which one do you want to try next?
日常的によく食べられるのは鶏肉だけど
Usually, chicken is the most commonly eaten one.
牛肉やラム肉は珍しいけど美味しいよね
Beef and lamb are less common, but they're delicious.
ビーフすっごく美味しいね！
The beef is so delicious!
エビ好きだよ〜
I love shrimp!
尻尾も食べる？
Do you eat the tail too?
多分？どうだろう？
Maybe? I wonder.
エビはエビだけどなんか違う
It's shrimp, but different somehow.
味付けが通常のSateと違って
The seasoning is different from regular Sate.
ピーナッツソースとかの定番じゃないけどすごく美味しい
It's not the classic peanut sauce, but it's very delicious.
バイバイオニオ〜ン
Bye-bye, onion!
ラムもピーナッツソースじゃないんだね
So the lamb doesn't have peanut sauce either.
なんの味だろう？
What flavor is this?
甘味が強い感じのソースだね
It's a sauce with a strong sweet flavor.
水飲むからちょっと待って
Wait a moment, I'm going to drink some water.
甘辛い感じかな...
Maybe a sweet and spicy flavor...
あ、後から辛さがくるやつだ
Ah, the spiciness comes after.
本当だ！じわじわ辛さがくる
You're right! The spice creeps up on you.
あ〜辛い
Ah, it's spicy!
どの調味料か分からないけどすごく美味しい
I don't know what spices they are, but it's so good.
5種類のうちどれが1番好きだった？
Which of the five was your favorite?
エビのやつが好き！
I like the shrimp one!
私は牛肉のサテが1番気に入ったかな
I think I liked the beef Sate best.
これまであまり牛肉のサテを食べたことがなかったからだと思うけど
Probably because I haven't had beef Sate very often before.
I haven't eaten beef sate that much before,
and this is so... - ...good!
We have more food!
Yeah, I'm crying.
No!
So I guess that's why
they didn't give us like rice.
Oh, it was really spicy!
It's okay, this is not spicy. - Yes! Mmm.
This is Mi Goreng.
Mi Goreng, Mi Goreng!
Yeah, so you ate the instant Mi Goreng already?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. - This is the not instant version.
I'm so happy this is not spicy.
Happy happy! - I like the spicy, but...
...I'm happy we get to rest. - Not now.
Ah, it's nice and chewy! - Mmm.
And they're thick noodles!
Yeah, the texture of the noodles is very... kenyal-kenyal.
Yeah, the texture of the noodles is very... chewy.
Kenyal-kenyal?
Chewy?
Kenyal-kenyal is Indonesian for mochi-mochi.
"Kenyal-kenyal" is Indonesian for chewy.
Ah, it's cute!
Kenyal-kenyal. Kenyal-kenyal! Kenyal-kenyal!
Chewy. Chewy! Chewy!
Everyone has different Mi Gorengs at home,
but this style, I really like this style.
So many, many toppings. - It's like Yakisoba.
Mmm, it is Indonesian Yakisoba.
Yakisoba, but sweet. Sweet Yakisoba.
So earlier we had Natto cousin,
now we have Yakisoba cousin.
Yakisoba cousin!
And finally, this is Bali's traditional dish
called Lawar.
Lawar! Lawar!
Actually, I've never had this before.
Really? - Yeah, so this is like my first time also.
Yay! - I'm so excited!
So in this dish, we have some peanuts.
Oh, it's peanuts! - Yeah, this one is peanuts.
I thought Natto. - It's not.
And then we have some buncis.
And then we have some green beans (buncis).
So buncis, English-de nan to iu no?
So how do you say buncis in English?
Green... - Green... Green what? Green...
Ah, buncis. - Buncis. Yeah.
So normally, this is served with pork.
They usually serve it with pork.
But because this edition is like halal edition,
so they replaced it with chicken.
Chicken, chicken. - Yeah, with chicken. Chicken.
Yummy, I'm so excited!
I wonder how this tastes like
cause there's also like shallots and everything.
Let's try it! - Let's try it!
Wait, I'll try the buncis first.
- Buncis. Itadakimasu!
Wait, I'll try the green beans first.
- Green beans. Thank you for the food!
Nom. Mmm, I like the buncis is very crunchy.
Nom. Mmm, I like the green beans, they're very crunchy.
Oh, it's like a snack!
Yeah, it is kind of like a snack. Actually, it is.
And it's salty.
I want to eat for oyatsu. - Yeah, yeah.
I want to eat it as a snack. - Yeah, yeah.
It's yummy! - Very good.
We've eaten so many things! - Yeah!
Is your stomach okay? - Yeah, okay.
Is there room? More room?
Cuz you know what comes after these meals?
For dessert? - Yes!
Okay, it's time for dessert! Let's go!
And what do we have here? We have mango pudding!
Look at these layers! It's so good.
What is this, like chocolate? I'm not sure.
Or like brown sugar?
Ah. - Let's taste it.
Yeah, let's taste it to be sure. Ooh.
Ooh, it's pudding! - Yeah.
It's so soft.
Okay, wait, I'll try, I'll try. - Okay.
Mmm! It's so creamy!
And the mango is also so sweet, yeah.
Like, I have no idea, but like this is so creamy,
and maybe there's like
a hint of coconut milk maybe? I'm not sure.
Ah, it's creamy. - It is, it is.
Wait, what's down here? What is the brown...
I'm curious about the brown stuff.
I'll get the brown one.
Ah... Like caramelized... Ah...
Oh, this one, this one. - Yeah, yeah, that one.
Mmm. Oh!
Caramel. - Mmm, so like the burnt caramelized flan.
Ah, yeah, yeah. - Wait, this is so good, guys.
Nice. - And we have more, really? Oh my gosh!
This is fried banana snack. - Fried banana!
It sounds yummy. - Yeah.
So fried banana is like... it's literally banana,
and then you have batter and then you deep fry it.
Must be good.
Yeah. It's a very famous...
It's a very famous snack in Indonesia.
We don't always eat it with ice cream,
but it's fancy, I guess. I'm not complaining.
Ah, smells good! Smells good.
Mmm, yeah. - The banana is really hot!
うーん！
Mmm!
あ、熱っ！
Ah, hot!
熱っ、熱い！
It's hot, so hot!
あ、熱い...
Ah, it's hot...
熱い！
It's hot!
バターが染みていて美味しいね
But the batter... I think the batter is delicious!
最高！！！
It's the best!!!
最高だね！
It's the best!
うん、これ本当に美味しい
Yes, this is very good.
甘さ控えめで、ちょうどいいよ
It's sweet, but not too sweet.
アップルパイみたいな感じ！
Like an apple pie!
うん！うん、確かに。美味しいね！
Mmm, yeah! Yeah, kind of! I like it.
カメラロールが、黙々とこれを食べてるだけの私たちの映像でいっぱいになっちゃうね（笑）
Camera roll's going to be just full of us eating this and saying nothing! (laughs)
いぇーい！
Yay!
完食！
[Finished]
今日は来てくれて、本当にありがとう、はあちゃま！
Thank you so much for coming today, Haachama!
ううん、誘ってくれてありがとう！
No, thank you so much for inviting me!
どうだった？楽しかった？
Was it good? Did you have fun?
楽しかったよ〜！私もとっても楽しかったよ、ありがとう！
So much fun! I had fun too, thank you!
今日はたくさんのインドネシア料理を食べたけど、
Now that you've tried so much Indonesian food,
次はどうする？もっとレベルアップするために！
What do we do next so we level you up more?
インドネシアへ行くよ！
I'll go to Indonesia!
（笑）そうだね！行こう！
(laughs) Yes! Let's go!
インドネシア料理、好きになったよ！
Now I like Indonesian food!
料理の次は、実際にインドネシアへ行こうね！
Indonesian food first, next you go on holiday to Indonesia!
今度は私が作るよ！インドネシア料理を！
I'll make it! I'll cook!
ええええ！？本当に！？やるの！？
Oh! Wow! You'll cook?!
はあちゃまがインドネシア料理を！？やろう！
Haachama cooking Indonesian dishes! Let's do it!
それから、お願いがあるんだけど...
And also, also, also, also...
日本のローカルな、あまり知られてない美味しい食事を食べに連れて行って！
Take me to eat some underrated Japanese food too!
日本のみんなが普段、どんなものを食べているのか知りたいの
I want to know what Japanese people eat.
私が教えてあげるよ！
I'll, I'll teach you!
日常的な食事を味わってみたい〜美味しいやつ！
Yes! Day-to-day Japanese people food, yummy!
美味しい！いぇーい！
Yummy! Yay!
ということでみんな！今後もはあちゃまとレイネのアドベンチャーを楽しみにしててね！
So, everyone, look forward to more Haachama and Reine adventures!
お楽しみに！
Alright!
ということで、スタジオへ戻しましょう！スタジオのレイネさん、聞こえますか？
Let's go back to the studio. Studio Reine, are you there?
スタジオのレイネさーん、取れますか〜？
Studio Reine-san, can you hear us?
はーい！スタジオのレイネです！
Hi! Studio Reine here!
はあちゃまとの日本でのインドネシア料理店への旅、どうでしたか？
So, what did you think of our trip to the Indonesian restaurant in Japan with Haachama?
うわ〜、本当に美味しそう！行きたーい！
Wow, that looks so delicious! I want to go!
今度みんなを連れて行くね！
I'll take you guys there next time!
やったー！ご飯、ご飯、ご飯！
Yay! Food, food, food!
お腹すいてきた〜（笑）
I'm getting hungry! (laughs)
それじゃあ次は、第2ゲームをやりましょう！
Alright, next up, let's play our second game!
いぇーい！
Yay!
ゲーム1と同様、誰が一番早くゴールに到達できるかを競います！
Well, just like in game one, we will be competing to see who can reach the goal the fastest.
よし！準備はいい？
Yeah! Okay, are you guys ready?
いいよー！いつでも！
Yeah! Ready!
このゲームでは、このアイテムを使います！
For this game, we will be using this item!
おお、ボールだ！
Oh, wow! A ball!
ビーチボールだね！いぇーい！
A beach ball! Yay!
プロバスケ選手（baller）になれたらよかったのにな
Man, I wish I was a baller.
もう少し身長が高ければよかったのに
I wish I was a little bit taller.
190cmのバスケ選手（baller）だったらな
I wish I had a six-foot-four baller.
可愛い女の子がいたら、電話するのに！
Or a girl who looked good, I would call her.
（笑）
(laughs)
ちょっと、暴力はダメだよ！サッカーじゃないんだから、やめて！
Whoa, the violence! This isn't soccer, alright? You knock that off.
カップが終わっちゃったね（笑）
The cup is over.
はいはい！次のゲームのルールは...
Okay, okay, okay. The rules for the next game...
超シンプルです！
is super simple.
このボールを両脚の間に挟みます。出産する時みたいにね！
You hold this ball between your legs like you're giving birth.
え、ちょっと（笑）
Wait, what? (laughs)
それから...
And...
こうやって、歩くんじゃなくて...
not walking, but...
そう、こんな感じで！
Yeah, so like this.
そして、ジャンプしながらレースをします！
And then, you guys will be racing while hopping.
えー！サッカーをするんだと思ってたのに！
Aw, I thought we were going to play football!
違うよ！サッカーは今度、来年やりましょう（笑）
No, you're not! Next time, next year, football, let's go!
サッカーやろう！フットボール国に行こう！
Let's go, let's go, football nation, let's go.
このゲームの名前は「ボラ・チャレンジ」です！
And the game is called the Bola Challenge!
「ボラ」は「ボール」という意味です！
\"Bola\" means ball.
ボラ・チャレンジ！ボラ！ボール！
Bola Challenge! Bola! Ball!
これが一番大きいボールだね
This is the biggest ball.
私のは絶対に小さいよ、スカートの都合上ね
Mine's definitely small, just because of the skirt situation.
あ、だからそのボールなんだね！
Oh, so that's why.
うん、そう。小さいボール。ちょっと、やめてよ（笑）
Yeah, small ball. Hey, hey, stop!
ということで、基本的にはボールを両脚に挟んで...
Okay, so basically, all you have to do is hold the ball...
スタートから折り返し地点まで跳んで、
between your legs and hop from start to the turnaround point,
そしてゴールまで戻ってきます。簡単でしょ？
and then make it to the finish line. Right? Simple, right?
うん！簡単だね！すごくシンプル！
Yeah! Simple? Very simple.
そう、でも実はひねり（特別ルール）があります！
Yeah, okay, well, there's a twist, actually.
もっと面白くするために、2つの追加ルールがあります！
To make things more interesting, we're adding two extra rules.
まず、お題が出されるので、レース中はお題について話し続けなければいけません！
First, you'll be given a topic, and you have to race while talking about it.
あー！なるほど！
Oh! Okay!
みんなおしゃべりは得意でしょ？だからお喋りしながら...
Yeah, so you guys are good at yapping, right?
ジャンプするの！？
While jumping?
ジャンプしながら喋ったことはないよ（笑）
I've never tried yapping while balling, okay?
新しいスキルを身につけるのに遅すぎることはないよ！
Never too late to pick up a new skill.
履歴書に書けるね（笑）
Put it on your resume.
それと前と同じように、2人ずつ競い合います。なので、パートナーとしっかり会話を続けてね！
Yeah, and just like before, two people will compete at a time. So make sure you keep chatting with your partner while you race.
対戦相手だけどパートナーってことね
Opponent, partner, same thing.
おしゃべりし続けないといけないんだね
Alright, the yapping has to...
大丈夫？ちょっとトリックを試そうとしたんだけど（笑）
Are you okay? I tried doing a trick, I'm sorry.
ごめんごめん（笑）
Sorry, sorry.
そして2つ目のルールは、折り返し地点を過ぎたら、相手の邪魔をしてもOKです！
Okay, and the second rule is, after you pass that point, you can try to mess with your opponent.
だから、こょこよしたり、何でもしていいよ！
So if you want to tickle your opponent...
え、ちょっと！やめて！（笑）
Wait! Stop!
私はそんなことしないから安心してね！
Hey, I'm not going to do that to you.
基本的にはそんな感じです！
Yeah, basically like that.
We tried this during rehearsal,
well, I tried,
and I guess it's going to be, you know...
It's kind of tiring, so it's your choice basically.
You can just, like,
focus on racing, or you know,
if you have... you're a little bit more, what's it, mischievous, you want to tickle,
you want to tickle your opponent?
Tickle?
Yeah, you want to,
yeah, you want to lift them up and kiss them, that's fine too.
Are you too ticklish?
I'm not ticklish.
I'm not.
I think she might be ticklish. No, I'm not ticklish at all.
Reine, use it to your advantage. Never let your opponent know your weakness.
Tickle tickle tickle tickle. No no no.
But anyway,
all right, everybody, let's get into position.
Calli and Kiara.
Oh boy, I'm first again.
That's fine.
You're going to be facing...
You're already getting started.
Don't make it too hard for yourself.
Yeah.
You make it harder for yourself.
Wait, what's our topic?
Wait wait wait, hold on hold on. I'm going to go here first.
Oh!
Which topic?
Okay,
your topic is...
Things I love about my cat!
Oh, easy! Right? 猫自慢。
Oh, easy! Right? Bragging about cats.
That's a pretty easy one.
You guys both have adorable cats at home, so go ahead and brag as much as you want.
Okay.
Yes.
That might actually help me forget that I'm tired.
Oh yeah, cats take that all away.
So fluffy, okay.
What about... can we talk about that cat over there?
No!
Focus on your game.
That's a secret agent disguised as a cat.
Or a cat disguised as a secret agent.
Okay.
Are you guys ready?
Yeah, ready as I'll ever be.
All right, on your marks.
Three, two, one, go!
Chuchu is so fluffy and cute. She has a bobble...
black stripe down the back of her... What are you doing?
Her tail is so fluffy and long.
No, what are you doing?
Wait, oh my god!
Should we increase the distance?
Should we make it a little further? Do we still have to finish it?
Well, tell me a little bit about your cats, Kiara.
Yes, so currently,
I'm not with my cats so that makes me really sad.
But my cat caretakers
are sending me videos of them and they're sleeping like on the towels
even though I said "Don't sleep on the towels because the towels are not supposed to have cat hair all over."
But it's okay, I forgive them. I just buy new towels so there are cat towels and there are human towels.
That's a good idea to separate them like that.
Oh, she's finished!
Yay! That was so good.
Nice job. Good job.
That was so good. Oh my.
Well done, well done. I respect the legwork. That was intense.
I mean, this is... I actually do this during my training anyway.
Oh!
Yeah, hold the ball between my legs and jump. So I kind of had an unfair advantage.
Oh, so you're... okay, you have that skill.
I do this every muscle training session.
You trained with balling.
Okay.
Well, let's announce your times, girls, please.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Yay!
頑張れ、頑張れ！
Go for it, go for it!
Well, I won, but who won?
Oh, that was a close one.
It was very, very close.
So, okay, set up, please.
All right.
So,
it was... it's close.
Can you say my time first?
Okay, your time first. Okay, let's see.
Kiara, your time was 46.5 seconds!
Oh yeah! That's pretty fast.
Yeah!
That's a crazy dance move. She showed us how to throw it down.
Okay, now Calli...
It was a close one.
Yeah, that was a really close one.
Your time was 10.5 seconds!
Oh my god!
I could've been a little faster, I guess.
This is me on a slow day, actually. Go Kiara!
Yeah, I need to work on my feelings and...
Feelings?
Oh, your feelings. How are you feeling?
I had an unfair advantage.
I just wish I was a baller.
Oh, first you got to be a little bit taller.
By a 6'4 Impala.
And then we'll talk.
Well, I hope that your match will be a little bit closer.
Oh, ganbare.
Oh, good luck.
What match? Our match?
Ganbatte.
Do your best.
Ganba, ganba. You're up.
Do your best, do your best. You're up.
Take your ball.
Go get your ball. Go get your ball.
Sorry, I left my ball.
Don't forget your balls. Get my ball. Don't forget.
Hey, can we make our balls meet?
What?
Hi, nice to meet you. This is my ball.
Nice to meet you too.
Oh, we just met.
We just met.
Do your balls know each other?
Not yet, not yet!
After this race...
...we'll get to know each other now.
Alrighty. Well then, it looks like I'm going to be tanto for this match.
Alrighty. Well then, it looks like I'm going to be in charge of this match.
Ayo.
So... here is your topic.
Okay? Compliment each other in Japanese!
ええー！？
What!?
No English, no Indonesian allowed.
This is a good challenge for somebody, or two people, who speak three languages!
That's right.
Kiara also speaks three languages.
So you'll have no excuse.
Compliment each other in German.
German?
Guten Morgen!
Good morning!
Danke schön! Danke schön!
Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
Okay. Are you ready?
And on your marks, get set, go!
ゼタ、可愛い！先輩、可愛い！
Zeta, you're cute! Senpai, you're cute!
ゼタ、髪が綺麗！
Zeta, your hair is beautiful!
先輩、足長い！
Senpai, your legs are long!
デートに行かない？
Do you want to go on a date?
デートに行こう！チューチューチュー！
Let's go on a date! Chu chu chu!
Wait, wait.
I think so. I'm pretty sure I heard some compliments.
It was a little hard to hear what they were saying, but they were definitely complimenting each other.
What were you saying to each other?
Um, I was saying "Zeta kawaii," "ashi nagai," and then...
Um, I was saying "Zeta is cute," "long legs," and then...
..."your hair is pretty," and then "let's go on a date sometime," and then I said "chu chu chu."
..."your hair is pretty," and then "let's go on a date sometime," and then I said "kiss, kiss, kiss."
Those are compliments. Yeah, those are compliments.
What did you say to her?
I said, "Wow, 君は素晴らしい!"
I said, "Wow, you are amazing!"
And, "拳が強い!"
And, "Your fists are strong!"
And, "根性!"
And, "Grit!"
And, "てて!"
And, "Hand in hand!"
Yeah, those are compliments. That was successful, then. Good job, team.
And we got the times ready? Maybe too?
Good job. Let's check out the times.
We both know each other now.
Let's meet! Let's meet!
Alrighty, fine, fine.
I want my ball to hang out with you guys too.
Oh, wow. We only just met, but this is kind of fun.
I don't know.
Do we have the times? Let's check them out. We probably have them now. I think I could tell who won, though.
Ah, got it. You saw it.
It was close!
It was definitely closer than ours.
Just like earlier, it was close.
Okay, we got it. The times... do you want to say them?
Now, Reine, your time was... 12 seconds!
Yay!
And Zeta...
大丈夫？ 大丈夫、大丈夫。
Are you okay? Yeah, I'm okay.
Zeta, your time was... 14 seconds!
Wow!
Good job! Any number with the number four in it is a good number.
It is a good number. So, the winner of your match was...
...Reine!
Yay!
How do you feel?
Yeah, I feel great. Energized.
Ready for more exercise?
Yeah, great.
It is rigged. She is the birthday girl, of course she would win.
Everyone, you all did an amazing job.
We finished both games, so we're going to total up everyone's times and announce the winner.
Yes, find out who has the shortest total time.
It's hot here in Indonesia today, isn't it?
Alright, take a breath, take a breath.
CPR, CPR, CPR please!
Kiara, you do it! Do you do it, you do the CPR.
I'm dying, somebody CPR please.
Kiara will do it.
I'm alive! Are you okay?
事故、事故！ 事故、事故！
Emergency, emergency! Emergency, emergency!
She lives! I'm alive!
お疲れ。お疲れ、you're alive. Congrats on being alive.
Good job. Good job, you're alive. Congrats on being alive.
Do we have the results yet?
Wait, wait, while we're waiting on the results, here's my sick trick.
Calli, catch! Okay, I'm ready.
Are you ready to catch? Yeah.
Well, it was a little low.
Again, again.
Three, two, one...
Nice!
Let's go, TakaMori! TakaMori ball masters!
TakaMori knows ball.
Wow, we're ballin'.
That was awesome, that was a sick trick. We should become like a football club.
Our team! Oh, results are in!
We got them, we got them. The results are in, and let's announce the winner, okay?
And let's start with... the fourth place! Drumroll please!
*drumroll*
Takanashi Kiara!
Four is the best number! Last place but I mean, first place in...
...in your hearts, right?
Yes! So true, so true.
Fourth place is first from the bottom!
あ、すごい！
Ah, that's amazing!
I'm so goi!
I'm so amazing!
Also, number one balloon.
Also, the number one balloon.
Number one baller.
You see how well she knows that ball.
Yeah, see?
Whoa! Whoa!
Okay, and then...
The third place is our very own beloved house cat!
Vestia Zeta!
Our beloved house cat, secret agent!
Yay, I'm third place!
Okay, hands please, hands please!
Yeah, she's so cute.
Okay, good girl!
Congratulations!
That's not how you dog-sit though.
Cat, dog, same thing, same thing.
Not the same animal, not the same animal.
They're adjacent, whatever.
Okay, and in second place...
...just missing out on the win...
It's Pavolia Reine!
Oh my god! Yay, girl! I know her!
Wait, Calli, you didn't let her win on her birthday?
Oh, should I... Wait, what? Should I have done that?
Is that, like, a manners thing?
Oh god, sorry, sorry!
No, no, I prepared something for the winner, so that's okay.
And that means our champion with the fastest time, Mr. Ball...
Mori Calliope!
Mr. Ball? Please don't hurt me.
Congratulations! - Thank you!
Thank you, oh my gosh! I appreciate it, I've been training.
So, Mori...
...who got the fastest time, has earned a very special trophy.
Thank you! - Ta-da-da-da-da!
Oh, trophy! I have to... can I touch my ball too?
Yes, this is a very special trophy for today!
Whoa, I like it!
Thank you! Thank you so much! Thank you!
Anyways, any comments? Any, you know, winner interview?
Um, this is really fun! I had such a great time enjoying Indonesia!
But more than anything, I'm glad we all got to have lots of fun on your very special day. Reine, thank you for inviting us...
...and sharing with us some of the games that, you know, you used to like to play. It was just a really good time, so thank you!
No, thank you so much, Calli, and thank you, Kiara and Zeta, for participating!
And that's all for the games. Thank you so much for playing with me, everyone!
Yay! Thank you!
And coming up next in the stream, I have a very, very special surprise!
A brand new song performance!
Whoa! New song, new song! New song, new song!
But before we get there, I want to show you...
...uh, the teaser video for the new song and introduce some merch!
So don't go anywhere and stay with us until the very end.
We will! Yay!
All right, now let's take a look at the teaser video for the new song!
Here you go!
Pavolia Reine New Original Song
Endless Blue
2026.09.09 24:00 RELEASE
[Pavolia Reine New Original Song: Endless Blue]
[Released on 2026.09.09 at 24:00]
How did you like the teaser video?
Yeah! Yeah! What are they doing?
You guys are so suspicious!
So, well, this new song is, you know my very first original song, Gate Open: START?
Yes! Yes!
So if Gate Open: START is the opening of an anime...
...this is kind of, you know, a little bit more mellow vibe, maybe like a second season opening of Gate Open: START.
I love that, yeah!
Reine anime when? Let's go!
Yay! I'd watch it!
Second season, omedetou! - Omedetou!
Second season, congratulations! - Congratulations!
Well, as I mentioned earlier, I'll be performing it later, so please look forward to it!
And now, before I perform the new song, I'd like to have my guests here...
...my beautiful, beautiful guests, help me introduce this year's birthday merch!
All right, everyone, get over here! We won't let you down!
Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Buy! Get out your wallet!
Ta-da!
Okay, first up, 'Take me with U' Acrylic Diorama Stand!
Featuring a beautiful illustration by Enji-sensei of me enjoying me-time with a beautiful view!
Whenever you go to a restaurant, please take me with you!
What are you guys doing?
Take your oshikatsu pictures! Don't forget oshikatsu!
Take your fan support pictures! Don't forget fan support!
Next...
おいおい、キアラ？
Oi oi, Kiara?
待って待って！あなた、これに出番あるの？
Wait, wait! Do you have a part in this?
うん、仕事があるんだよ！
Yes, I have a job to do.
2つ目のアイテムを紹介します！トラベルタオルー！
I will introduce the second item: the Travel Towel!
トラベルタオルー！
Travel Towel!
名前に騙されないでね。これはとっても万能なタオルで、
Don't let the name fool you, this is a super versatile towel...
旅行だけでなく、普段の生活でも使えます。脇を拭いて、脇を拭いて！
that you can use not only for traveling, but also in your everyday life. Wipe your armpits, wipe your armpits!
例えば、次のフェスでも大活躍すること間違いなし！
It sure will come in handy at the next fest too, for example!
タオル！タオル！タオル！タオル！
Towel! Towel! Towel! Towel!
次、次、次、次。
And next, next, next, next.
そして3つ目のアイテムは、じゃじゃーん！ミーアヤムボウル！
And the third item is... ta-da! Mie Ayam Bowl!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ミーアヤム！アヤム！ミーアヤム！美味しい、美味しい！
Mie Ayam! Ayam! Mie Ayam! Delicious, delicious!
名前が示す通り、このボウルはミーアヤムを食べるのにぴったりですが、ラーメンや、
As the name suggests, this bowl is perfect for eating Mie Ayam, but it's also great for ramen,
スープ、その他あらゆる料理にも最適です。
soup, and all kinds of other dishes.
だから、たくさん使ってもらえると思います。何にでも使えますよ！
So, I'm sure you'll get lots of use for it. You can use it for anything!
キャットフードを入れてもいいよね！
You can even put cat food into it!
帽子としても使えるよ！
You can even use it as a hat!
何でもありだね！アヤム、アヤム...
Whatever works!
そう、このボウルで美味しい食事をたくさん楽しんでね！
Yeah, I hope this bowl helps you enjoy lots of tasty meals!
素晴らしい！そして最後になりますが、4つ目のアイテム…冗談、最後じゃないよ、4つ目のアイテム！
Very nice! And last but certainly not least, the fourth item—just kidding, it's not last, it's the fourth item!
死神だから4番に配属されたんだけどね。
But I was assigned number four because I am a Shinigami.
4つ目のアイテムは、愛らしい旅のパートナー、ぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
The fourth item is... the lovely travel partner plushie keychain!
すべての旅行や冒険に持っていくのにぴったりのサイズです。
It is the perfect size to bring on all your trips and your adventures.
この衣装を着た可愛い小さなレイネをどこにでも連れて行って、一緒にたくさん楽しんでくださいね！
Take this adorable little Reine in her costume with you wherever you go and have lots of fun together!
イェーイ！素晴らしい！
Yay! Spectacular!
イェーイ！そして今回は、特別なシチュエーションボイスもあります。
Yay! And this time, I also have a special situational voice:
「不気味な旅のパートナー」！
"Spooky travel partner"!
3カ国語で収録された怖い話が入っています！
It includes scary stories recorded in three languages!
すごい！マルチリンガル！超怖い！
Great! Multilingual! So scary!
英語、インドネシア語、日本語…今回はミックスボイスはありません、ごめんね、ミックス言語のボイスはありません。
English, Indonesian, Japanese... No mixed voice this time, sorry, no mixed language voice.
そしてもちろん、フルセットには限定のポストカード特典が付いてきます！
And of course, the full set comes with an exclusive postcard bonus!
お見逃しなく！
Don't miss out!
手書きサイン入りのポストカードも数量限定でご用意していますので、このチャンスをお見逃しなく！
We also have a limited number of postcards with my handwritten signature, so make sure you don't miss out on this chance!
レイネのサインが欲しい！
I want Reine's autograph!
そう、レイネのサインが欲しい！
Yes, I want Reine's autograph!
レイネのサインが欲しい！
I want Reine's autograph!
いやいや、私、私を先にして！超高速で買うから！どいてどいて。
Hey, no, me! Me first! I'm going to buy real fast! Get out of my way.
私のライフィーのスピードに勝てる？
Can you beat my lifey speed?
絶対無理！でも、みんな最前列で会おうね、行こう。
Definitely not! But I'll see you guys in the pit, let's go.
レイネのサインのために戦うんだ。みんな準備しておけよ。
Fighting for Reine's signature. All you guys better be ready.
もう十分に戦ったんじゃないの？
Didn't we already fight enough?
いや、今度はファンと戦いたいんだ。そう、次はファンの番だ。
Well, I want to fight the fans now. Yes, it's their turn now.
次は君たちだ！
You guys are next!
ということで、グッズ紹介は以上になります！
And that wraps up our merch introduction!
よし、下がって、下がって、下がって！
Okay, move back, back, back!
下がって、下がって、下がって…どこに下がるの？
Back back back... Back to where?
自分がどこにいたか忘れちゃった！
I forgot where I was!
自分がどこにいたか分からないよ！
I don't know where I was!
ここ、多分ここでいいと思う。みんな、ふぅ！
Here, maybe here is fine. Okay guys, whew!
今年の誕生日会は本当に楽しかったです！
This year's birthday celebration was so much fun!
2つの異なるロケ撮影に行けて、みんなと一緒に過ごせて、たくさんの素晴らしい思い出ができました。
I got to go to two different location shoots, spend time with everyone, and make so many great memories.
だから、私の誕生日をこんなに楽しくしてくれて、本当に、本当にありがとうございました！
So, thank you, thank you so much again for making my birthday so fun!
どういたしまして！おいで、おいで！
You're welcome! Bring it in, bring it in!
レイネが1歳年上になったね。
Reine is one year older.
1歳年上になりました！
I'm one year older!
私に近づいたこと、おめでとう。
Congrats on getting closer to me.
髪の毛が白くなってきてるよ。
Your hair is turning grey.
あなたのもね！
Ours is too!
そして、あっという間に配信の最後の部分に達してしまいました。
And now, before we know it, we've reached the final part of the stream.
新曲のパフォーマンスの時間です！
And it is time for the new song performance!
ちょっと待って、みんなに見せたいものがあるの。ちょっと取ってくるね。
Wait, hold on, I gotta show you something, I'm going to get something.
何を取ってくるの？どこに行くの？
What are you gonna get? Where is she going?
もしかしてあれかな？
Is it what I think it is?
私の愛しい、愛しいベイビー！
My beautiful, beautiful baby!
わぁ！何それ！ベース！レイネのベースだ！
Woah! Oh my god! Bass! It's the Reine bass!
ステッカーを見て！このステッカー、みんな見覚えある？
Look at the stickers! Do you guys recognize these stickers?
おおー！
Ooh!
よし、これには本当に、本当に一生懸命取り組んだので、みんなに楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです。
All right, I worked really, really hard on this so I hope you all can enjoy it.
それじゃあ、みんな新曲のタイトルを一緒に言ってくれる？
All right, can everyone say the title of the new song together with me?
よし、いこう！
Okay, let's go!
せーの…
Se-no...
エンドレス・ブルー！
Endless Blue!
Endless Blue
作詞：藤原優樹 作曲・編曲：長谷川大介
Lyrics: Yuki Fujiwara | Composition & Arrangement: Daisuke Hasegawa
[インストルメンタル]
[Instrumental Intro]
飾り付けた言葉でなんて 本当の鼓動隠してたんだ
I was hiding my true heartbeat behind decorative words...
折りたたんだ羽は 見えない空に焦がれてた
My folded wings were longing for an invisible sky.
パズルなら壊してしまった 散らばる欠片 バラバラ
If it were a puzzle, I would have broken it, scattered pieces fell apart.
誰かに似た色じゃ意味がない わかってるから
Because I know a color that looks like someone else's is meaningless.
旅立ちはあの青空のせいだ
My departure is all because of that blue sky.
誤魔化せない憧れに気づいたから
Because I realized an admiration that cannot be deceived.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable urge,
動き出したストーリーの先には
at the end of the story that has begun to move,
不安も もろい思いさえも 染めてゆく
it dyes even my anxiety and fragile feelings.
想像より眩しい空が広がってるはずでしょう<
A sky brighter than imagined must be spreading out, right?
扉を開け行こう
Let's open the door and go.
[インストルメンタル]
[Instrumental Break]
有耶無耶に進む昨日も 叫び傷む今日も
Yesterday, which moved forward vaguely, and today, which screams and hurts,
今更なんて言って 願いの色は薄れていった
saying "it's too late now," the color of my wish faded away.
痛みなら飲み干してしまおう また乗り越えてみせるよ
If it's pain, I'll drink it all up; I'll show you I can overcome it again.
私でいることにためらう弱さはもういらない
I no longer need the weakness of hesitating to be myself.
広げた羽は飾りじゃないよ
My spread wings are not just for show.
鮮やかな夢を纏おう その覚悟がここにあるから
Let's wear a vivid dream, because that determination is right here.
[インストルメンタル]
[Instrumental Break]
幻想の夜重ねて
Piling up night after night of illusions,
漂うように歩いていたよ
I was walking as if drifting along.
途方もなく遠くて 挫けそうになっても
Even if it's endlessly far and I'm about to give up,
この声は羽ばたけるその時を待っていたんだ
this voice of mine was waiting for the moment to take flight.
もう一度叫んでみるよ
I'll try to scream once more!
終わりなんてない旅を続けたくて
Wanting to continue a journey with no end,
進んでいくストーリーの向こうへと
I move forward, beyond the story.
この声で果てない空を渡っていく
With this voice, I'll cross the endless sky.
まだ知らない遥かな青に
To the far-off blue that I don't know yet,
胸を膨らませて
with my heart full of expectation,
無限の明日がきっと待っているから
because a limitless tomorrow is surely waiting.
扉を開け行こう
Let's open the door and go.
[インストルメンタル]
[Instrumental Outro]
Reine B'Day Classroom
Field Trip: Food & Games with Akai Haato
Reine's Birthday Classroom